<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="dental_care_id_0">
    	"Overview:\n\nA permanent tooth that is knocked out can sometimes be reimplanted. In most cases, only permanent, adult teeth are reimplanted into the mouth. Baby teeth are usually left out."					
        "Causes:\n\nTooth accidents are commonly caused by:\n\n
		    \nAccidental falls
		    \nSports-related trauma
		    \nFighting
		    \nCar accidents
		    \nBiting on hard food"
		    
		    "Treatment:\n\nUse one of the following options to transport the tooth:\n\n

    \n1.Try to replace the tooth in the socket, to the level of adjacent teeth. Bite down gently on gauze or a wet tea bag to help keep it in place. The surrounding teeth can be used as anchors. Care must be taken not to swallow the tooth.
    \n2.If the tooth cannot be replaced in the socket, place it in a container and cover with a small amount of whole milk or saliva. The tooth can also be carried between lower lip and lower gum or under the tongue.
    \n3.A tooth-saving storage device (Save-a-Tooth, EMT Tooth Saver) may be available at your dentist's office. Such a kit contains a travel case and fluid solution. Consider buying one for your home first aid kit.
		    "
		    "For additional first aid, follow these steps:\n\n

    \n1.Apply a cold compress to the mouth and gums for pain.
    \n2.Apply direct pressure, using gauze, to control bleeding.
    \n3.Get dental help immediately. The sooner dental attention is received, the better the chances are for successful reimplantation.
		    "
        
      </string>
      <string name="dental_care_id_1">
          "Overview :\n\n Tooth decay is one of the most common of all disorders, second only to the common cold. It usually occurs in children and young adults but can affect any person. It is a common cause of tooth loss in younger people.

			Bacteria are normally present in the mouth. The bacteria convert all foods especially sugar and starch  into acids. Bacteria, acid, food debris, and saliva combine in the mouth to form a sticky substance called plaque that adheres to the teeth. It is most prominent on the back molars, just above the gum line on all teeth, and at the edges of fillings. Plaque that is not removed from the teeth mineralizes into tartar. Plaque and tartar irritate the gums, resulting in gingivitis and ultimately periodontitis.

			Plaque begins to build up on teeth within 20 minutes after eating (the time when most bacterial activity occurs). If this plaque is not removed thoroughly and routinely, tooth decay will not only begin, but flourish."
          
          
          "Causes:\n\nTooth decay is one of the most common of all disorders, second only to the common cold. It usually occurs in children and young adults but can affect any person. It is a common cause of tooth loss in younger people.

			Bacteria are normally present in the mouth. The bacteria convert all foods , especially sugar and starch , into acids. Bacteria, acid, food debris, and saliva combine in the mouth to form a sticky substance called plaque that adheres to the teeth. It is most prominent on the back molars, just above the gum line on all teeth, and at the edges of fillings. Plaque that is not removed from the teeth mineralizes into tartar. Plaque and tartar irritate the gums, resulting in gingivitis and ultimately periodontitis.

			Plaque begins to build up on teeth within 20 minutes after eating (the time when most bacterial activity occurs). If this plaque is not removed thoroughly and routinely, tooth decay will not only begin, but flourish."			
      
      "Treatment:\n\nTreatment may involve:

    \nFillings
    \nCrowns
    \nRoot canals\n\n
    Dentists fill teeth by removing the decayed tooth material with a drill and replacing it with a material such as silver alloy, gold, porcelain, or composite resin. Porcelain and composite resin more closely match the natural tooth appearance, and may be preferred for front teeth. Many dentists consider silver amalgam (alloy) and gold to be stronger, and these materials are often used on back teeth. There is a trend to use high strength composite resin in the back teeth as well.

\nCrowns or "caps" are used if tooth decay is extensive and there is limited tooth structure, which may cause weakened teeth. Large fillings and weak teeth increase the risk of the tooth breaking. The decayed or weakened area is removed and repaired. A crown is fitted over the remainder of the tooth. Crowns are often made of gold, porcelain, or porcelain attached to metal.

\nA root canal is recommended if the nerve in a tooth dies from decay or injury. The center of the tooth, including the nerve and blood vessel tissue (pulp), is removed along with decayed portions of the tooth. The roots are filled with a sealing material. The tooth is filled, and a crown may be placed over the tooth if needed.
      "
      
      </string>
	  <string name="dental_care_id_2">
               
	      "Overview:\n\nGingivitis is a form of periodontal disease. Periodontal disease involves inflammation and infection that destroys the tissues that support the teeth, including the gums, the periodontal ligaments, and the tooth sockets (alveolar bone).

			Gingivitis is due to the long-term effects of plaque deposits. Plaque is a sticky material made of bacteria, mucus, and food debris that develops on the exposed parts of the teeth. It is a major cause of tooth decay. If you do not remove plaque, it turns into a hard deposit called tartar that becomes trapped at the base of the tooth. Plaque and tartar irritate and inflame the gums. Bacteria and the toxins they produce cause the gums to become infected, swollen, and tender."

			"Causes:\n\nThe following raise your risk for developing gingivitis:\n\n
			\nGeneral illness
			\nPoor dental hygiene
			\nPregnancy (hormonal changes increase the sensitivity of the gums)
			\nUncontrolled diabetes\n\n
			Misaligned teeth, rough edges of fillings, and ill-fitting or unclean mouth appliances (such as braces, dentures, bridges, and crowns) can irritate the gums and increase the risk of gingivitis.
			\nMedications such as phenytoin and birth control pills, and heavy metals such as lead and bismuth are also associated with gingivitis."
			
			"Treatment:\n\nThe goal is to reduce inflammation. The teeth are cleaned thoroughly by the dentist or dental hygienist. This may involve various instruments or devices to loosen and remove deposits from the teeth.

\nCareful oral hygiene is necessary after professional tooth cleaning. The dentist or hygienist will show you how to brush and floss. Professional tooth cleaning in addition to brushing and flossing may be recommended twice per year or more frequently for severe cases. Antibacterial mouth rinses or other aids may be recommended in addition to frequent, careful, tooth brushing and flossing.

\nRepair of misaligned teeth or replacement of dental and orthodontic appliances may be recommended. Any other related illnesses or conditions should be treated."

"Prevention:\n\nGood oral hygiene is the best prevention against gingivitis because it removes the plaque that causes the disorder. The teeth should be brushed at least twice daily and flossed gently at least once per day. For people who are prone to gingivitis, brushing and flossing may be recommended after every meal and at bedtime. Consult the dentist or dental hygienist for instructions on proper brushing and flossing techniques.

\nSpecial appliances or tools may be recommended by the dentist for use by people who are particularly prone to plaque deposits. The use of supplements does not replace thorough brushing and flossing. Appliances and tools may include special toothpicks, toothbrushes, water irrigation, or other devices."
               
	      
      </string>
     <string name="dental_care_id_3">          "Overview:\n\nTeeth start to pass through the gums (emerge) during infancy, and again when the primary (baby) teeth are replaced by the permanent teeth.

If a tooth fails to emerge, or emerges only partially, it is considered to be impacted. The most common teeth to become impacted are the wisdom teeth (the third set of molars). They are the last teeth to emerge, usually between the ages of 17 and 21.An impacted tooth remains stuck in gum tissue or bone for various reasons. It may be that the area is just overcrowded and there's no room for the teeth to emerge. For example, the jaw may be too small to fit the wisdom teeth. Teeth may also become twisted, tilted, or displaced as they try to emerge, resulting in impacted teeth."

"Causes:\n\n
    \nBad breath
    \nDifficulty opening the mouth (occasionally)
    \nPain or tenderness of the gums (gingiva) or jaw bone
    \nProlonged headache or jaw ache
    \nRedness and swelling of the gums around the impacted tooth
    \nSwollen lymph nodes of the neck (occasionally)
    \nUnpleasant taste when biting down on or near the area
    \nVisible gap where a tooth did not emerge\n\n
    Your dentist will look for swollen tissue over the area where a tooth has not emerged, or has only partially emerged. The impacted tooth may be pressing on nearby teeth."
    
    "Treatment:\n\nNo treatment may be needed if the impacted tooth is not causing any problems.

\nOver-the-counter pain relievers may help if the impacted tooth causes discomfort. Warm salt water (one-half teaspoon of salt in one cup of water) or over-the-counter mouthwashes may be soothing to the gums.

\nRemoval of the tooth (extraction) is the usual treatment for an impacted tooth. This is usually done in the dentist's office, but difficult cases may require an oral surgeon. Antibiotics may be prescribed before the extraction if the tooth is infected."
"Prevention:\n\n"
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_4">          "Overview:\n\nLeukoplakia mainly affects the mucus membranes of the mouth. It is caused by irritation. Sores usually develop on the tongue, but they may also appear on the insides of the cheek.

Irritation in the mouth may be caused by rough teeth or rough places on dentures, fillings, and crowns. It may also result from smoking or other tobacco use (smoker's keratosis). Persons who smoke pipes are at high risk for developing this condition, as are those who hold chewing tobacco or snuff in their mouth for a long period of time."
"Causes:\n\n
\nLeukoplakia patches may develop on the external female genital area, but the cause is unknown.

\nLeukoplakia may become cancerous.

\nThe disorder is most common in elderly persons."

"Treatment:\n\nThe goal of treatment is to get rid of the lesion. Removing the source of irritation is important and may cause the lesion to disappear.

    \nTreat dental causes such as rough teeth, irregular denture surface, or fillings as soon as possible.
    \nStop smoking or using other tobacco products.
    \nDo not drink alcohol."
    "Prevention:\n\n

\nMinimize or stop smoking or using other tobacco products. Do not drink alcohol, or limit your number of alcoholic drinks. Have rough teeth treated and dental appliances repaired promptly.

\nSafer sexual practices minimize the risk of contracting sexually-transmitted diseases, including HIV."
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_5">    		"Overview:\n\nLudwig's angina is an infection of the floor of the mouth underneath the tongue that is due to bacteria.Ludwig's angina is a type of cellulitis that involves the floor of the mouth, under the tongue. It often occurs after an infection of the roots of the teeth (such as tooth abscess) or a mouth injury.

This condition is uncommon in children."
		"Causes:\n\ncauses includes:
    \nBreathing difficulty
    \nConfusion or other mental changes
    \nFever
    \nNeck pain
    \nNeck swelling
    \nRedness of the neck
    \nWeakness, fatigue, excess tiredness"
    "Treatment:\n\nIf the swelling blocks the airway, emergency medical help is needed to maintain an open airway. This may involve placing a breathing tube through the mouth or nose and into the lungs, or surgery called a tracheostomy that creates an opening through the neck into the windpipe.

Antibiotics, usually penicillin or a penicillin-like medication, are given to fight the infection. They are usually given through a vein until symptoms go away. Antibiotics taken by mouth may be continued until tests show that the bacteria have gone away."
		"Prevention:\n\nRegular visits to the dentist, and prompt treatment of mouth or tooth infections can prevent the conditions that increase the risk of developing Ludwig's angina."
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_6">    		"Overview:\n\nOcclusion refers to the alignment of teeth and the way that the upper and lower teeth fit together (bite). Ideally, all upper teeth fit slightly over the lower teeth. The points of the molars fit the grooves of the opposite molar.

The upper teeth keep the cheeks and lips from being bitten and the lower teeth protect the tongue.

Malocclusion is most often hereditary, which means the condition is passed down through families. There may be a difference between the size of the upper and lower jaws or between jaw and tooth size, resulting in overcrowding of teeth or in abnormal bite patterns."		
          "Causes:\n\ncauses of malocclusion include:

    \nChildhood habits such as thumb sucking, tongue thrusting, pacifier use beyond age 3, and prolonged use of a bottle
    \nExtra teeth, lost teeth, impacted teeth, or abnormally shaped teeth
    \nIll-fitting dental fillings, crowns, appliances, retainers, or braces
    \nMisalignment of jaw fractures after a severe injury
    \nTumors of the mouth and jaw"
    "Treatment:\n\nVery few people have perfect teeth alignment. However, most problems are so minor that they do not require treatment.

Malocclusion is the most common reason for referral to an orthodontist.

By treating moderate or severe malocclusion, the teeth are easier to clean and there is less risk of tooth decay and periodontal diseases (gingivitis or periodontitis). Treatment eliminates strain on the teeth, jaws, and muscles, which lessens the risk of breaking a tooth and may reduce symptoms of temporomandibular joint disorders."
		"Prevention:\n\nMany types of malocclusion are not preventable. Control of habits such as thumb sucking may be necessary in some cases. However, early detection and treatment may optimize the time and method of treatment needed."
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_7">    		"Overview:\n\nCold sores are caused by the herpes simplex virus and are very contagious. Usually, you will have tenderness, tingling, or burning before the actual sore appears. Cold sores usually begin as blisters and then crust over.

The herpes virus can live in your body for years. It only appears as a mouth sore when something triggers it, such as:

    \nAnother illness, especially if there is a fever
    \nHormone changes (such as menstruation)
    \nStress
    \nSun exposure"
    "Causes:\n\nMost mouth sores are cold sores (also called fever blisters), canker sores, or other irritation caused by:

    \nA sharp or broken tooth or poorly fitting dentures
    \nBiting your cheek, tongue, or lip
    \nBurning your mouth from hot food or drinks
    \nBraces
    \nChewing tobacco"	
    "Treatment :\n\nMouth sores usually go away in 10 to 14 days, even if you don't do anything. They sometimes last up to 6 weeks. The following steps can make you feel better:

    \nAvoid hot beverages and foods, spicy and salty foods, and citrus.
    \nGargle with cool water or eat popsicles. This is helpful if you have a mouth burn.
    \nTake pain relievers like acetaminophen.

\n\nFor canker sores:

    \nRinse with salt water.
    \nApply a thin paste of baking soda and water.
    \nMix 1 part hydrogen peroxide with 1 part water and apply this mixture to the sores using a cotton swab.
    \nFor more severe cases, treatments include fluocinonide gel (Lidex), anti-inflammatory amlexanox paste (Aphthasol), or chlorhexidine gluconate (Peridex) mouthwash."
    	"Prevention:\n\nYou can reduce your chance of getting common mouth sores by:

    \nAvoiding very hot foods or beverages
    \nReducing stress and practicing relaxation techniques like yoga or meditation

\n\nYou can avoid irritation by:

    \nChewing slowly
    \nUsing a soft-bristle toothbrush
    \nVisiting your dentist right away if you have a sharp or broken tooth or misfitting dentures"
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_8">    		"Overview:\n\nMouth ulcers are sores or open lesions in the mouth."
    		"Causes:\n\nMouth ulcers are caused by many disorders. These include:

    \nCanker sores
    \nGingivostomatitis
    \nHerpes simplex (fever blister)
    \nLeukoplakia
    \nOral cancer
    \nOral lichen planus
    \nOral thrush"
    "Treatment:\n\nThe goal of treatment is to relieve symptoms. The cause, if known, should be treated.

Gentle, thorough oral hygiene may relieve some of the symptoms. Topical (rubbed on) antihistamines, antacids, corticosteroids, or other soothing preparations may be recommended for applying directly to the ulcer.

Avoid hot or spicy foods, which often increase the pain of mouth ulcers."
		"Prevention:\n\nGood oral hygiene may help prevent some types of mouth ulcers, as well as some complications from mouth ulcers. Good oral hygiene includes brushing the teeth at least twice per day, flossing at least daily, and getting regular professional dental cleanings and examinations."		
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_9">    		"Overview:\n\nNatal teeth are relatively uncommon, appearing in about one in every 2,000 to 3,000 births. Although most natal teeth are isolated incidents, their presence may be associated with certain medical syndromes.

Natal teeth generally develop on the lower gum, where the central incisor teeth will appear. They have little root structure and are attached to the end of the gum by soft tissue and are often wobbly."		
          "Causes:\n\nMost of the time, natal teeth are not related to a medical condition. However, sometimes they may be associated with:

    \nEllis-van Creveld syndrome
    \nHallermann-Streiff syndrome
    \nPierre Robin syndrome
    \nSoto syndrome"
    "Treatment:\n\nIf the teeth are not removed, keep them clean by gently wiping the gums and teeth with a clean, damp cloth. Examine the infant's gums and tongue frequently to make sure the teeth are not causing injury."
    "Prevention:\n\n"
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_10">    		"Overview:\n\nOral cancer is cancer of the mouth."
    		"Causes:\n\nOral cancer most commonly involves the lips or the tongue. It may also occur on the:

    \nCheek lining
    \nFloor of the mouth
    \nGums (gingiva)
    \nRoof of the mouth (palate)

\n\nMost oral cancers are a type called squamous cell carcinomas. These tend to spread quickly."
		"Treatment:\n\nSurgery to remove the tumor is usually recommended if the tumor is small enough. Surgery may be used together with radiation therapy and chemotherapy for larger tumors. Surgery is not commonly done if the cancer has spread to lymph nodes in the neck.

Other treatments may include speech therapy or other therapy to improve movement, chewing, swallowing, and speech."
		"Prevention:\n\n
    \nAvoid smoking or other tobacco use
    \nHave dental problems corrected
    \nLimit or avoid alcohol use
    \nPractice good oral hygiene"
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_11">        "Overview:\n\nOral thrush is a disorder caused by infection of the mouth with the fungus (yeast) Candida albicans."
        "Causes:\n\nThe mouth normally contains many microorganisms. One of these normal microorganisms is the fungus Candida albicans, which is the same fungus associated with vaginal yeast infections or other Candida infections. The growth of Candida is normally kept under control by the presence of normal bacteria.

Uncontrolled overgrowth of Candida in the mouth may be caused by factors that reduce the natural resistance, such as illness, stress, long-term use of corticosteroids or medications that suppress the immune system, and immune disorders such as (AIDS).

It may also be caused by conditions that upset the balance of normal microorganisms in the mouth. This is most commonly associated with use of antibiotics, but it may also occur with uncontrolled diabetes mellitus and with the hormonal changes associated with pregnancy or the use of birth control pills. "
        "Treatment:\n\n"
        "Prevention:\n\n"
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_12">    		"Overview:\n\nPeriodontitis is inflammation and infection of the ligaments and bones that support the teeth."
    		"Causes:\n\nPeriodontitis occurs when inflammation or infection of the gums (gingivitis) is untreated or treatment is delayed. Infection and inflammation spreads from the gums (gingiva) to the ligaments and bone that support the teeth. Loss of support causes the teeth to become loose and eventually fall out. Periodontitis is the primary cause of tooth loss in adults. This disorder is uncommon in childhood but increases during adolescence."
    		"Treatment:\n\nThe goal of treatment is to reduce inflammation, eliminate pockets if present, and address any underlying causes. Rough surfaces of teeth or dental appliances should be repaired. General illness or other conditions should be treated."
			"Prevention:\n\nGood oral hygiene is the best means of prevention. This includes thorough tooth brushing and flossing, and regular professional dental cleaning. The prevention and treatment of gingivitis reduces the risk of development of periodontitis."
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_13">    		"Overview:\n\nYou should get specific instructions from your dentist or hygienist on how to correctly brush and floss. But in general, recommendations for preventing and removing tartar or plaque on your teeth include:

    \nBrush at least twice a day with a brush that is not too large for your mouth and that has soft, rounded bristles. The brush should let you reach every surface in your mouth easily, and the toothpaste should contain fluoride.
    \nFloss gently at least twice a day. This is important to prevent gum disease.
    \nSee your dentist or oral hygienist every 6 months for a thorough teeth cleaning and oral examination.

Dental sealants are a means of protecting teeth from decay by sealing over healthy pits, fissures, and grooves in the teeth. Well-balanced meals are also recommended for maintaining healthy teeth and gums."
		"Causes:\n\n"
		"Treatment:\n\n"
		"Prevention:\n\nYou should get specific instructions from your dentist or hygienist on how to correctly brush and floss. But in general, recommendations for preventing and removing tartar or plaque on your teeth include:

    \nBrush at least twice a day with a brush that is not too large for your mouth and that has soft, rounded bristles. The brush should let you reach every surface in your mouth easily, and the toothpaste should contain fluoride.
    \nFloss gently at least twice a day. This is important to prevent gum disease.
    \nSee your dentist or oral hygienist every 6 months for a thorough teeth cleaning and oral examination.
		"		
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_14">    		"Overview:\n\nMany different things can cause tooth discoloration. The change in color may affect the entire tooth, or just appear as spots or lines in the tooth enamel.

Your genes influence your tooth color. Other things that can affect tooth color include:

    \nCongenital diseases
    \nEnvironmental factors
    \nInfections

Inherited diseases may affect the thickness of enamel or the calcium or protein content of the enamel, which can cause color changes. Metabolic diseases may cause changes in tooth color and shape."
		"Causes:\n\n
	\nAntibiotic tetracycline use before age 8
    \nEating or drinking items that temporarily stain the teeth, such as tea or coffee
    \nGenetic defects that affect the tooth enamel, such as dentinogenesis and amelogenesis
    \nHigh fever at an age when teeth are forming
    \nPoor oral hygiene
    \nPorphyria
    \nSevere neonatal jaundice
    \nToo much fluoride from environmental sources (natural high water fluoride levels) or overuse of fluoride rinses, toothpaste, and fluoride supplements"
    "Treatment:\n\nGood oral hygiene will help if the teeth are stained from a food or fluid, or if the abnormal color is the result of poor hygiene.

It is appropriate to consult your dentist for abnormally colored teeth. However, if the color seems to be related to a medical condition, your regular health care provider should also be consulted."
	"Prevention:\n\n"		
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_15">    		"Overview:\n\nThe appearance of normal teeth varies, especially the molars. Abnormally shaped teeth can result from many different conditions. Specific diseases can have a profound effect on tooth shape, tooth color, time of appearance, or absence of teeth."
    		"Causes:\n\n
    \nCongenital syphilis
    \nCerebral palsy
    \nEctodermal dysplasia , anhidrotic
    \nIncontinentia pigmenti achromians
    \nCleidocranial dysostosis
    \nEhlers-Danlos syndrome
    \nEllis-van Creveld syndrome"
    "Treatment:\n\n"
    "Prevention:\n\n"		
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_16">    		"Overview:\n\nA tooth abscess is a collection of infected material (pus) resulting from a bacterial infection in the center of a tooth."
    		"Causes:\n\nA tooth abscess is a complication of tooth decay. It may also result from trauma to the tooth, such as when a tooth is broken or chipped. Openings in the tooth enamel allow bacteria to infect the center of the tooth (the pulp). Infection may spread out from the root of the tooth and to the bones supporting the tooth."
    		"Treatment:\n\n

The goals of treatment are to cure the infection, save the tooth, and prevent complications.

Antibiotics may be given to fight the infection. Warm salt-water rinses may be soothing. Over-the-counter pain relievers may relieve the toothache and fever.

Do NOT place aspirin directly over the tooth or gums, because this increases irritation of the tissues and can result in mouth ulcers.

A root canal may be recommended in an attempt to save the tooth.

If there is a severe infection, the tooth may be removed or surgery may be needed to drain the abscess. Some people may need to be admitted to the hospital."
			"Prevention:\n\n

Prompt treatment of dental caries reduces the risk of tooth abscess. Traumatized teeth should be examined promptly by the dentist."		
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_17">    		"Overview:\n\nA toothache is generally the result of dental cavities (tooth decay) or sometimes an infection. Tooth decay is often caused by poor dental hygiene, although the tendency to get tooth decay is partly inherited.

Sometimes, pain that's felt in the tooth is actually due to pain in other parts of the body. This is called referred pain or radiating pain. For example, an earache may sometimes cause tooth pain."
			"Causes:\n\n

    \nAbscessed tooth
    \nEarache
    \nInjury to the jaw or mouth
    \nHeart attack (can include jaw pain, neck pain, or toothache)
    \nSinusitis
    \nTooth decay"
    "Treatment:\n\nOver-the-counter pain medications may be used while waiting to see the dentist or primary health care provider.

For toothaches caused by a tooth abscess, the dentist may recommend antibiotic therapy and other treatments, like root canal.

To prevent tooth decay, use good oral hygiene. A low sugar diet is recommended along with regular flossing, brushing with fluoride toothpaste, and regular professional cleaning. Sealants and fluoride applications by the dentist are important for preventing tooth decay."		
     "Prevention:\n\n"     
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_18">    		"Overview:\n\nTrench mouth is a painful bacterial infection that involves swelling (inflammation) and ulcers in the gums (gingiva)."
    		"Causes:\n\n

Trench mouth is a painful form of gum swelling (gingivitis). The term "trench mouth" comes from World War I, when the disorder was common among soldiers.

The mouth normally contains a balance of different bacteria. Trench mouth occurs when there are too many normal mouth bacteria. The gums become infected and develop painful ulcers. Viruses may be involved in allowing the bacteria to grow too much."
		"Treatment:\n\n

The goals of treatment are to cure the infection and relieve symptoms. Your health care provider may prescribe antibiotics if you have a fever.

Good oral hygiene is vital to the treatment of trench mouth. Brush and floss your teeth thoroughly as often as possible, at least twice a day and preferably after each meal and at bedtime.

Salt water rinses (1/2 teaspoon of salt in 1 cup of water) may soothe sore gums. Hydrogen peroxide, used to rinse the gums, is often recommended to remove dead or dying gum tissue."
		"Prevention:\n\n

\n\nPreventive measures include:

    \nGood general health
    \nGood nutrition
    \nGood oral hygiene, including thorough tooth brushing and flossing
    \nLearning ways to cope with stress
    \nRegular professional dental cleaning and examination
    \nStopping smoking"
</string>
    <string name="dental_care_id_19">    		"Overview:\n\nWidely spaced teeth can be a temporary condition related to normal growth and the development of adult teeth. Wide spacing can also occur as a result of several diseases or continued growth of the jawbone."
    		"Causes:\n\n

    \nAcromegaly
    \nEllis-van Creveld syndrome
    \nInjury
    \nMorquio syndrome
    \nNormal growth (temporary widening)
    \nPossible gum disease
    \nSanfilippo syndrome
    \nTooth shifting due to missing teeth"
    "Treatment:\n\n"
    "Prevention:\n\n"		
</string>
</resources>
