<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="dental_care_id_0">
    	"Overview:\n\nA permanent tooth that is knocked out can sometimes be reimplanted. In most cases, only permanent, adult teeth are reimplanted into the mouth. Baby teeth are usually left out."					
        "Causes:\n\nTooth accidents are commonly caused by:\n\n
		    \nAccidental falls
		    \nSports-related trauma
		    \nFighting
		    \nCar accidents
		    \nBiting on hard food"
		    
		    "Treatment:\n\nUse one of the following options to transport the tooth:\n\n

    \n1.Try to replace the tooth in the socket, to the level of adjacent teeth. Bite down gently on gauze or a wet tea bag to help keep it in place. The surrounding teeth can be used as anchors. Care must be taken not to swallow the tooth.
    \n2.If the tooth cannot be replaced in the socket, place it in a container and cover with a small amount of whole milk or saliva. The tooth can also be carried between lower lip and lower gum or under the tongue.
    \n3.A tooth-saving storage device (Save-a-Tooth, EMT Tooth Saver) may be available at your dentist's office. Such a kit contains a travel case and fluid solution. Consider buying one for your home first aid kit.
		    "
		    "For additional first aid, follow these steps:\n\n

    \n1.Apply a cold compress to the mouth and gums for pain.
    \n2.Apply direct pressure, using gauze, to control bleeding.
    \n3.Get dental help immediately. The sooner dental attention is received, the better the chances are for successful reimplantation.
		    "
        
      </string>
      <string name="dental_care_id_1">
          "Overview :\n\n Tooth decay is one of the most common of all disorders, second only to the common cold. It usually occurs in children and young adults but can affect any person. It is a common cause of tooth loss in younger people.

			Bacteria are normally present in the mouth. The bacteria convert all foods especially sugar and starch  into acids. Bacteria, acid, food debris, and saliva combine in the mouth to form a sticky substance called plaque that adheres to the teeth. It is most prominent on the back molars, just above the gum line on all teeth, and at the edges of fillings. Plaque that is not removed from the teeth mineralizes into tartar. Plaque and tartar irritate the gums, resulting in gingivitis and ultimately periodontitis.

			Plaque begins to build up on teeth within 20 minutes after eating (the time when most bacterial activity occurs). If this plaque is not removed thoroughly and routinely, tooth decay will not only begin, but flourish."
          
          
          "Causes:\n\nTooth decay is one of the most common of all disorders, second only to the common cold. It usually occurs in children and young adults but can affect any person. It is a common cause of tooth loss in younger people.

			Bacteria are normally present in the mouth. The bacteria convert all foods , especially sugar and starch , into acids. Bacteria, acid, food debris, and saliva combine in the mouth to form a sticky substance called plaque that adheres to the teeth. It is most prominent on the back molars, just above the gum line on all teeth, and at the edges of fillings. Plaque that is not removed from the teeth mineralizes into tartar. Plaque and tartar irritate the gums, resulting in gingivitis and ultimately periodontitis.

			Plaque begins to build up on teeth within 20 minutes after eating (the time when most bacterial activity occurs). If this plaque is not removed thoroughly and routinely, tooth decay will not only begin, but flourish."			
      
      "Treatment:\n\nTreatment may involve:

    \nFillings
    \nCrowns
    \nRoot canals\n\n
    Dentists fill teeth by removing the decayed tooth material with a drill and replacing it with a material such as silver alloy, gold, porcelain, or composite resin. Porcelain and composite resin more closely match the natural tooth appearance, and may be preferred for front teeth. Many dentists consider silver amalgam (alloy) and gold to be stronger, and these materials are often used on back teeth. There is a trend to use high strength composite resin in the back teeth as well.

\nCrowns or "caps" are used if tooth decay is extensive and there is limited tooth structure, which may cause weakened teeth. Large fillings and weak teeth increase the risk of the tooth breaking. The decayed or weakened area is removed and repaired. A crown is fitted over the remainder of the tooth. Crowns are often made of gold, porcelain, or porcelain attached to metal.

\nA root canal is recommended if the nerve in a tooth dies from decay or injury. The center of the tooth, including the nerve and blood vessel tissue (pulp), is removed along with decayed portions of the tooth. The roots are filled with a sealing material. The tooth is filled, and a crown may be placed over the tooth if needed.
      "
      
      </string>
	  <string name="dental_care_id_2">
               
	      "Overview:\n\nGingivitis is a form of periodontal disease. Periodontal disease involves inflammation and infection that destroys the tissues that support the teeth, including the gums, the periodontal ligaments, and the tooth sockets (alveolar bone).

			Gingivitis is due to the long-term effects of plaque deposits. Plaque is a sticky material made of bacteria, mucus, and food debris that develops on the exposed parts of the teeth. It is a major cause of tooth decay. If you do not remove plaque, it turns into a hard deposit called tartar that becomes trapped at the base of the tooth. Plaque and tartar irritate and inflame the gums. Bacteria and the toxins they produce cause the gums to become infected, swollen, and tender."

			"Causes:\n\nThe following raise your risk for developing gingivitis:\n\n
			\nGeneral illness
			\nPoor dental hygiene
			\nPregnancy (hormonal changes increase the sensitivity of the gums)
			\nUncontrolled diabetes\n\n
			Misaligned teeth, rough edges of fillings, and ill-fitting or unclean mouth appliances (such as braces, dentures, bridges, and crowns) can irritate the gums and increase the risk of gingivitis.
			\nMedications such as phenytoin and birth control pills, and heavy metals such as lead and bismuth are also associated with gingivitis."
			
			"Treatment:\n\nThe goal is to reduce inflammation. The teeth are cleaned thoroughly by the dentist or dental hygienist. This may involve various instruments or devices to loosen and remove deposits from the teeth.

\nCareful oral hygiene is necessary after professional tooth cleaning. The dentist or hygienist will show you how to brush and floss. Professional tooth cleaning in addition to brushing and flossing may be recommended twice per year or more frequently for severe cases. Antibacterial mouth rinses or other aids may be recommended in addition to frequent, careful, tooth brushing and flossing.

\nRepair of misaligned teeth or replacement of dental and orthodontic appliances may be recommended. Any other related illnesses or conditions should be treated."

"Prevention:\n\nGood oral hygiene is the best prevention against gingivitis because it removes the plaque that causes the disorder. The teeth should be brushed at least twice daily and flossed gently at least once per day. For people who are prone to gingivitis, brushing and flossing may be recommended after every meal and at bedtime. Consult the dentist or dental hygienist for instructions on proper brushing and flossing techniques.

\nSpecial appliances or tools may be recommended by the dentist for use by people who are particularly prone to plaque deposits. The use of supplements does not replace thorough brushing and flossing. Appliances and tools may include special toothpicks, toothbrushes, water irrigation, or other devices."
               
	      
      </string>
      <string name="dental_care_id_3">
               
      </string>
      <string name="dental_care_id_4">
               
          	
      </string>
      <string name="dental_care_id_5">
    				
          
      </string>
    
</resources>
